indiegogo.com 2017-12-26

# Privacy Policy - Indiegogo

## Indiegogo, Inc.

This Privacy Policy was last modified on and is effective as of August 1, 2017.

Indiegogo, Inc. (“ **Indiegogo** ,” “ **we** ,” or “ **us** “, “ **our** “) **knows** that you care how Personal Information about you is collected, used, shared and stored. “ **Personal Information** ” means information which personally identifies you or another.

This Privacy Policy explains what Personal Information will be collected by Indiegogo when you use our Website: https://www.indiegogo.com/ and related services (the “ **Service** “), how Personal Information will be used, and how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of Personal Information.

This Privacy Policy should be read along with our Terms of Use posted at: <https://www.indiegogo.com/about/terms> (“ **Agreement** “), the Partner Terms posted at: <https://www.indiegogo.com/partners/terms>, and Indiegogo’s Cookie Policy posted at: [https://www.indiegogo.com/about/cookies](https://learn.indiegogo.com/cookie-policy/) and all other operating rules, policies and procedures and additional terms and conditions published on our Website (all of which are incorporated by reference) which governs your use of our Website and Service. Capitalized terms, if not defined in this Privacy Policy, are defined in the Agreement.

### EU-US & Swiss-US Privacy-Shield

Indiegogo, Inc. participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. We are committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

We are responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. We comply with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, we are subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

### Mobile Privacy

We may offer you the ability to connect with our Website, or use our applications, services, and tools using a mobile device, either through a mobile application or via a mobile optimized website. The provisions of this Privacy Policy apply to all such mobile access and use of mobile devices. This Privacy Policy will be referenced by all such mobile applications or mobile optimized websites.

### Personal Information We Collect or You May Provide

You provide us Personal Information when you register to be a User:

  * Your name
  * Your email address
  * Your Facebook information if you are signing up via Facebook connect (This will authenticate your identity and link your Facebook Profile information, such as your name and email address, to your Indiegogo account. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Website to your profile page to share with others within your network)
  * You may provide your location

If you create a Campaign, or join as a Campaign team member, you will provide us with the following Personal Information in addition to the Personal Information you provide when you register to be a User:

  * Your legal person or business name
  * Your legal physical address
  * Your Tax ID (if you are a business)
  * Your telephone number
  * Your date of birth
  * Your PayPal account information (if accepting payments via PayPal)
  * Your bank account information.

As a Contributor, you may provide:

  * Your name
  * Your email address
  * Ship-to information
  * Your billing name and address
  * Your PayPal e-mail address

You may be asked further information in order to help validate your identity:

  * Your gender
  * Your driver’s license information, government issued identification number
  * Other personally identifiable information as we need for verification

We may obtain address information about you from third party sources, such as LexisNexis, for fraud prevention or for legal compliance.

We may also collect Personal Information from you as a result of your email communications with us or your Posts which we may retain along with our responses.

As a Campaign Owner, you can invite others who are helping you with your campaign to join your campaign team. We will ask you for this person’s email address and send him or her an email invite to join your team. Indiegogo collects this email address for the purpose of sending this invite. This person may contact us at [privacy@indiegogo.com](mailto:privacy@indiegogo.com) to request that we remove this information.

You can sign up for or sign in to your Indiegogo account using Facebook Connect. When you sign in using Facebook Connect, Indiegogo will receive the following info: your public profile, friend list and email address. Indiegogo uses this info to authenticate your identity, display your number of Facebook friends on your Indiegogo Profile page, show you Campaigns your friends have funded, and link your Facebook Profile information to your Indiegogo account. Facebook Connect gives you the option to post information about your activities on this Website to your profile page to share with others within your network. You can disconnect Facebook Connect under your Indiegogo account settings page.

Any Personal Information you Post as User Content is available to the public without any expectation of privacy or confidentiality. Copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other Users have copied or stored your User Content even if you remove the User Content. Your name and location are publicly displayed in your profile page. To request removal of your personal information from these areas of the site, contact us using the information below. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. The profile you create on our site will be publically visible. You may change the visibility settings of your Contributions, and the types of information it may disclose, on the “My Contributions” page, and/or when you take specific actions on the site that provide you the option of anonymity.

We display personal testimonials of satisfied users on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us using the information below. We collect your location based information for the purpose of tailoring search to reflect results in your area. We will only share this information with our mapping provider for the sole purpose of providing you with this service.

When you use our mobile site, we may receive information about your location and your mobile device, including a unique identifier for your device. We may use this information to provide you with location based services, search results, and other personalized content. Most mobile devices allow you to control or disable location services in the device’s setting’s menu. If you have questions about how to disable your device’s location services, we recommend you contact your mobile service carrier or the manufacturer of your particular device.

### How We Use Your Personal Information

We use your Personal Information to operate, maintain, and provide to you the Service and conduct our business. For example (and not limited) to:

  * Register as a User and to identify you when you sign-in to your account
  * Administer your account or funds
  * Respond to your inquiries, customer service requests, complaints or your job application
  * Verify activity as we deem necessary
  * Send you a newsletter or other promotional communications
  * Conduct research and analyze data to improve our Service or customize our communications with you
  * Communicate with you

### How We Share Your Personal Information with Third Parties

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your Personal Information to third parties.

We may share your Personal information:

  * As required by law, such as to comply with reporting requirements, a subpoena, or similar legal process.
  * In connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity or as we believe reasonably necessary to protect or enforce our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others.
  * In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
  * With any other user, contributor, campaign owner or third party with your prior consent to do so as described in this Policy.

If you are a Contributor, we share your name, email and shipping address with the Campaign Owner or Campaign team member for delivery of Perks.

If you are a Campaign Owner, we may share your name, email address, and other contact information with any Contributor who alleges that you have failed to comply with your Campaign commitments such as Perk fulfillment.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as processing your payments, accepting job applications and offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information _only as necessary to provide_ these services to us and are obligated to keep your information confidential. Some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content from our service providers while preserving the look and feel of our site, such as when you enter credit card information. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to https://www.indiegogo.com/.

If Indiegogo is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets or bankruptcy, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Website of any change in ownership or uses of your Personal Information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your Personal Information.

### How We Store and Protect Your Personal Information

We may store Personal Information in locations outside our direct control (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers).

We use Security Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology to encrypt sensitive personal information (such as your payment information and geolocation) before it travels over the internet. Credit card numbers are never stored on our database or servers.

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Website, you can contact us at [privacy@indiegogo.com](mailto:privacy@indiegogo.com).

### Compromise of Personal Information

We will promptly notify those persons whose Personal Information is compromised. Notwithstanding, Indiegogo does not accept liability for any unintentional disclosure or a disclosure that occurs due to a security breach of our systems or facilities.

### User Access and Choice

You may, of course, decline to submit Personal Information to us; in which case, you may not be able to become a User or use certain Services.

If your Personal Information changes, you may correct, update, amend, remove, or ask to have it removed by making the change on your user account “Settings” page, by contacting the email address listed below. Upon request we will provide you with information about whether we hold, any of your personal information. If you no longer desire our service, you may deactivate/delete your account entirely from the account “Settings” page, or contact us directly. We will respond to your request within 30 days.

We will retain your Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your Personal Information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### Notification, Electronic Communication and Opt-Out

You consent to our using your email address to send you Service-related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail. You may not opt out of some Service-related communications. You can change the frequency of many Service-related communications by changing the settings in the “Settings” section.

Upon registration, or on other areas of the site, you may opt-in to receive periodic messages from us, including changes to features of the Service, newsletters, promotions and special offers. If you wish to subscribe to these emails, we will use your name and email address to send them to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing email preferences manager on your account settings page or you can contact us at [privacy@indiegogo.com](mailto:privacy@indiegogo.com). Opting out may prevent you from receiving email messages regarding updates, improvements, or offers.

### Children’s Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. Indiegogo does not knowingly collect or solicit Personal Information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are between the ages of 13 and 17, please use our Service with adult supervision. If you are under 13, please do not send any Personal Information to us. If we learn that we have collected Personal Information from a child under age 13, we will remove that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any Personal Information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at the contact information below.

This site complies with the California Eraser law. If you are a California resident, a minor, and you have publicly posted personally identifiable content, you may request such content be removed from our site, by providing a link to the content, your age, and contacting us at the information below. This site is not responsible for content you made public that is taken from this site and posted to another site.

### Tracking Technologies

Our policies are found at: <https://www.indiegogo.com/about/cookies>.

### Links to Other Websites, Blogs/Forums and Social Media Widgets

Our Site includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Indiegogo. When you use a link to go from our Website to another website, such as that of our payments processors, the privacy statement for the other website governs. We encourage you to carefully read and understand the privacy statement of any website you visit.

Our Website offers a publicly accessible blog. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be displayed publicly and read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog, contact us at [privacy@indiegogo.com](mailto:privacy@indiegogo.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Our Website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### English Language

The English version of this Privacy Policy governs. All disputes, claims and causes of action (and related proceedings) will be communicated in English.

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

If we make a material change to our privacy policies and procedures as to the collection, use or disclosure of your Personal Information, we will post a notice of those changes on our Website or notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it, prior to the change becoming effective. You are bound by changes to the Privacy Policy when you use the site after those changes have been posted. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Website, please contact us at [privacy@indiegogo.com](mailto:privacy@indiegogo.com) or at 965 Mission Street, San Francisco, CA 94103.
